Stride convolutions
is another piece of
the basic building block of
convolutions as using
convolution neural networks.
Let me show you an example.
Let's say you want to
convolve this serves by
seven image with this
three by three filter.
Except that instead of
doing the usual way,
we're going to do it
with a stride of two.
What that means, is you take
the element wise product as
usual in this upper
left three by
three region and then
multiply and add,
and that gives you 91.
But then instead of stepping
the blue box over by one step,
we're going to step
it over by two steps.
We're going to make it hop
over two steps like so.
Notice how the upper
left-hand corner has
gone from this start
to this start,
jumping over one position.
Then you do the usual
element-wise product and summing,
that gives you tones of 100.
Now we're going
to do that again,
and make the blue box
jump over by two steps.
You end up there and
that gives you 83.
Now when you go to the next row,
you again actually take two
steps instead of one step.
We're going to move the
blue box over there.
Notice how we're skipping
over one of the positions.
Then just gives you 69,
and now you gain
step over two steps.
This gives you 91, and so on.
So 127.
Then for the final row,
44, 72, and 74.
In this example, we convolve
with a seven by
seven matrix of a,
three by three matrix,
and we get a, three
by three output.
The input and output
dimensions turns
out to be governed by
the following formula.
If you have an n by
n image convolve
with an f by f filter.
If you use adding,
p and stride s. In this example,
s is equal to two.
Then you end up with an
output that is n plus 2p,
minus f. Now because you're
stepping s steps at
a time this up just
one step at a time,
you know divide by s plus 1,
and then by the same thing.
In our example we have,
7+0-3 divided by 2,
that's a stride plus
one equals, let's see,
that's 4/2+1=3,
which is why we wind up with
this three by three output.
Now, just one last detail,
which is one of this
fraction is not an integer.
In that case, we're going
to round this down.
This notation denotes
the four or something.
This is also called
the floor of z.
It means taking z,
and rounding down to
the nearest integer.
If the way this
is implemented is
that you take this type of
blue box multiplication only
if the blue box is fully
contained within the image or
the image plus the padding.
If any of this blue box,
part of it hangs
outside then you
just do not do that computation.
Then it turns out that if
that's a convention
that your feedback,
the filter must lie entirely
within your image or
the image plus the
padding region
before there's a corresponding
output generator.
That's convention. Then
the right thing to do,
to compute the output
dimension is to round down,
in case this n+2p-f/s
is not an integer.
Just to summarize
the dimensions,
if you have an n by n
matrix or n by n image,
that you convolve with an
f by f matrix and if I
filter with padding
p and stride s,
then the output size,
will have this dimension.
It is nice we can choose
all of these numbers,
so that isn't integer,
although sometimes
you don't have to do
that and rounding down
this is just fine as well.
But please feel free
to work through
a few examples of
values of n, f, p,
and s for yourself to convince
yourself if you want,
that this formula is correct
for the output size.
Now, before moving on,
there is a technical
comment I want to make
about cross-correlation
verses convolutions.
This won't affect
what you have to
do to implement convolution
neural networks.
But depending on the DVD,
different math textbook or
signal processing textbook,
there is one other
possible inconsistency
in the notation.
Which is that if you look at
a typical math textbook the way
that the convolution is defined,
before doing the element-wise
product and summing,
there's actually one other step
that you would first take,
which is to convolve
this six by six matrix,
and this three by three filter,
you first take the
three by three filter,
and flip it on the
horizontal as well as
the vertical axis.
There's 3, 4, 5
102 minus 197 will
become three goes here,
four goes there,
five goes there.
Then the second
row 201 minus 197.
But this is really taking
the three by three filter,
and mirroring it both on
the vertical and the
horizontal axis.
Then it was this flipped matrix
that you would then
copy over here.
To compute the output,
you would take 2*7 and so on.
You actually multiply
out the elements of
this filter matrix in order
to compute the upper left-hand,
most elements of the four
by four output as follows.
Then you take those nine
numbers and your shift them
over by one, and so on.
The way we've defined
the convolution operation
in these videos
is that we've skipped
this mirroring operation.
Technically what
we're actually doing?
Really the operation we've
been using for the
last few videos
is sometimes cross-correlation
instead of convolution.
That in the deep
learning literature,
by convention, we just call
this the convolution operation.
Just to summarize,
by convention,
in machine learning,
we usually do
not bother with this
flipping operation.
Technically this operation is
maybe better called
cross-correlation.
But most of the deep
learning literature just
causes the convolution operator.
I'm going to use that convention
in these videos as well,
and if you read a lot of the
machine learning literature,
you find most people
would just call this,
the convolution operator without
bothering to use these flips.
It turns out that in
signal processing or in certain
branches of mathematics,
doing the flipping
in the definition of
convolution causes
convolution operator,
to enjoy this property that
A convolve with B,
convolve with C,
is equal to A convolve with B,
convolve with C. And this is
called associativity
in mathematics.
This is nice for some signal
processing applications.
But for deep neural networks,
it really doesn't matter,
and so omitting this
double mirroring operation
just simplifies the code,
and mixing neural
network just as well.
By convention, most of us
just call this convolution.
Even though, the
mathematicians prefer to
call this cross-correlation
sometimes.
But this should not affect
anything you have to
implement in their
permanent exercises,
and should not
affect your ability
to read and understand the
deep learning literature.
You've now seen how to
carry out convolutions,
and you've seen how to use
padding as well as
strides for convolutions.
But so far all we've been
using is convolutions
over matrices like over
a six by six matrix.
In the next video,
you'll see how to
carry out convolutions
over volumes.
This will make why you can do
a convolution suddenly
much more powerful.
Let's go on to the next video.